<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section version="5.0" xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://www.docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink http://www.docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/xlink.xsd" xml:base="./../" xml:id="jBPMReleaseNotes640" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:ns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <title>New and Noteworthy in jBPM 6.4.0</title>
  <para>The following features were added to jBPM 6.4</para>
  
  <section>
    <title>New jBPM Process &amp; Task Dashboard</title>
    <para>The jBPM Process Dashboard has been entirely rewritten in this version and now is based on
      a native workbench perspective instead of a separated web application. The main goal is to deliver
      a better user experience, thanks to a much more appealing as well as polished user interface.</para>

    <figure>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/BAM/ProcessesDashboard.png" format="PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>

    <para>This dashboard version also provides the ability to navigate from the graphical indicators to any of the
      related process or task instances. Now, end users can easily find out the instances that are related to a given
      indicator and deep into their details as well.</para>

    <figure>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/BAM/ProcessesDashboardInstanceDetails.png" format="PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>

    <para>The resulting dashboard is more fluent, more interactive and with a better integration with the jBPM runtime.</para>

  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Task variables auditing</title>
    <para>By default process variables are stored in audit tables (VariableInstanceLog) that allows
      simplified access to variable values without need to load individual process instances.
      Moreover that provides option to search by process variables and process variable values e.g.
      to find process instances that have given value for given variable.</para>
    <para>This was missing for task variables as task variables were not stored in any audit tables.
      This has been improved in version 6.4.0 and now task variables are stored in audit table
      (TaskVariableImpl) by default. It does follow the same mechanism as for process variables -
      variable.toString() is the value stored in table. With this services and query APIs have been
      enhanced to take advantage of this support and to search for tasks by their variables.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Process and task variables indexation</title>
    <para>By default process and task variables are indexed with simplest possible mechanism - that
      is variable.toString() while for some object this can be sufficient, like simple types, for
      others it can cause significant problems when performing queries. To solve the problem process
      and task variables are equipped with pluggable indexation. This is realized by two interfaces
      that shall be implemented to provide custom indexation behavior.<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>org.kie.internal.process.ProcessVariableIndexer</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>org.kie.internal.task.api.TaskVariableIndexer</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>details about how to use the indexers can be found in  Audit log section of the
      documentation</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>QueryService</title>
    <para>QueryService that is an addition to jbpm services, brings in power of Dashbuilder DataSets
      (SQL based) to jbpm services. This allows more tailored queries that can include both jBPM
      tables and external tables such as external system data. With this users are in control of
      what data and how data are going to be queried.</para>
    <para>Dashbuilder DataSet introduce concept of building "data base views" for part of the data
      that can later on be filtered to find relevant data for given invocation.</para>
    <para>QueryService is available for all add-ons for services meanign pure java, CDI and
      EJB.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Pluggable Task deadlines notification listeners</title>
    <para>One of task deadlines actions is notification which by default is implemented as email
      notification. Although this type of notification does not always fit the requirement. To allow
      custom notification to be used, jBPM 6.4 was enhanced to support pluggable notification
      listeners. Notification is realized as broadcast, meaning all available listeners will be
      invoked, although each listener can decide if it shall react to given notification or not. For
      instance email notification listener will only send email if it's properly configured (with
      mail server etc) otherwise it will ignore the notification.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Ability to show bussiness data at task list.</title>
  </section>
  <section>
    <para>The user can now create a specific filter that provides domain specific columns to be
      added to a task list. When the user creates a custom filter for a specific task name the task
      variables are enabled as columns. </para>
    <para>The custom filter that activates the capability to display task variables as columns is
      set a filter with the restriction Name="taskName".</para>
    <figure>
      <title>Filter by task name creation</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Console/task-filter_taskname.png" format="PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    <para> When the filter with the restriction over a specific task name is applied, the task
      associated variables appear as a selectable columns, to the task list. </para>
    <figure>
      <title>task list with task name restriction applied</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Console/task-var_as_columns.png" format="PNG" maxwidth="700"
            />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Process Documentation.</title>
  </section>
  <section>
    <para>Users are able to view and share process documentation during business process modelling.
    Process documentation is dynamically updated as users are working on their business process.</para>
    <para>Users can print the documentation or view it as a png file.</para>
    <para>Process Documentation includes the following sections:
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Process Overview (general info, process variables, globals, and imports)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Process Element Details (totals, and specific element information)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Process Image</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <figure>
      <title>Process Documentation - Element Details</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/Designer/processdocumentation.png" format="PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
  </section>

</section>
