<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section version="5.0"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://www.docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink http://www.docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/xlink.xsd"
    xml:base="../" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xml:id="shared.Eclipse.KieNavigator"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:ns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    <title>Kie Navigator View</title>
    <para>The Kie Navigator is a new view in the Eclipse Tooling as of version 6.3. The Kie
        Navigator View is accessed from the Eclipse <emphasis role="bold">Window->Show
            View</emphasis> main menu:</para>
    <figure>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/Eclipse/KieNavigator/Image1.png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para>In order to use the Kie Navigator View, you must first define an Application Server in the
        WST Servers View. So, initially the Kie Navigator View will look like this:</para>
    <figure>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/Eclipse/KieNavigator/Image2.png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para> Clicking on the link “Use the Servers View to create a new server…” will open the Servers
        View where a new server definition can be created. Management of the server, including
        startup and shutdown is done from here. Note that Drools/jBPM requires certain additional
        JVM and server startup options, which must be added to the server startup configuration.
        Once a new server has been defined, open the server configuration page (double click on the
        newly created server entry) and the server Overview page is opened: </para>
    <figure>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/Eclipse/KieNavigator/Image3.png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para>Clicking the “Open launch configuration” link opens the following dialog:</para>
    <figure>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/Eclipse/KieNavigator/Image4.png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para>Here the user can enter the app server and JVM arguments to properly configure startup of
        the Kie web service. See the Drools/jBPM documentation for more information about these
        arguments.</para>

    <para>Alternatively, the app server and Kie web service application can be started from a
        command-line using either the provided Ant demo scripts or any other custom startup script.
        Note that starting from the Servers view may cause the app server to be shut down when
        exiting Eclipse. A server can also be configured in Eclipse for external management (see the
        “Server Behavior” section in the above screenshot.)</para>

    <para>Once the server has been configured and started, the Kie Navigator View will recognize the
        server and attempt to communicate with the Kie web service. The view now looks something
        like this:</para>
    <figure>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/Eclipse/KieNavigator/Image5.png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para>In this screenshot several nodes have been expanded to show all possible situations. At
        the root of this view is the app server. The Kie Navigator View is designed to support
        multiple servers, but each must obviously be configured a different hostname and/or HTTP
        port number. This, for example, allows management of development, test and production
        servers.</para>

    <para>Below the server level are Organizational Units and Repositories. Repositories that are
        not currently associated with an Organizational Unit appear directly under the Server root
        node. Below the Organizational Unit level are the associated Repositories, and below the
        Repositories are Projects contained in the Repository.</para>

    <para>A Repository can either be available (<inlinemediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/Eclipse/KieNavigator/Image6.png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject>) or unavailable (<inlinemediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/Eclipse/KieNavigator/Image7.png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject>) in the Workspace; a Repository is only available if it has been
        “imported” (see <link linkend="shared.Eclipse.KieNavigator.properties.organization.import">Context Menus</link>, below) from the Kie web server.</para>

    <para>Similarly, a Project can either be available (<inlinemediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/Eclipse/KieNavigator/Image8.png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject>) or unavailable (<inlinemediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/Eclipse/KieNavigator/Image9.png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject>) depending on whether it has been “imported”. When a Project has been
        imported, it behaves exactly the same as if it were being viewed in the Eclipse Project
        Explorer or Navigator; that is, all of the same menu actions available in the Project
        Explorer are also available in the Kie Navigator View. Also, all of the icon decorators and
        labels on project folders are the same as in Project Explorer.</para>

    <section>
        <title>Context Menus</title>
        <para>This section describes the context menu actions available for each type of node in the
            Kie Navigator tree.</para>
        <section>
            <title>Server</title>
            <figure>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/Eclipse/KieNavigator/Image10.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Refresh</emphasis> - causes a refresh of the entire viewer by making REST calls to the server to update the tree hierarchy.</para></listitem>
                    <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Create Organization…</emphasis> - creates a new Organizational Unit with information collected from the following dialog:</para>
                        <figure>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="images/Eclipse/KieNavigator/Image11.png"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject>
                        </figure>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Properties</emphasis> - displays the Server
                            Properties dialog (see the <link
                                linkend="shared.Eclipse.KieNavigator.properties.server">Property
                                Pages</link> section below.)</para></listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Organizational Unit</title>
            <figure>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/Eclipse/KieNavigator/Image12.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Add Repository...</emphasis> - adds a Repository
                            that is not already associated with any other Organizational Unit to
                            this Organization. A selection dialog containing a list of all
                            unassociated Repositories will be displayed, from which you can select a
                            Repository to add to the Organizational Unit.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Create Repository...</emphasis> - creates a new
                            Repository with information collected from the following dialog:</para>
                        <figure>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="images/Eclipse/KieNavigator/Image13.png"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject>
                        </figure>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Delete Organization...</emphasis> - deletes the
                            selected Organizational Unit and dissociates any Repositories that were
                            associated with this Organization. The Repositories are <emphasis
                                role="bold">not</emphasis> deleted.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Properties</emphasis> - displays the Organizational Unit
                            Properties dialog (see the <link
                                linkend="shared.Eclipse.KieNavigator.properties.organization">Property
                                Pages</link> section below.)</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Repository</title>
            <figure>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/Eclipse/KieNavigator/Image14.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem xml:id="shared.Eclipse.KieNavigator.properties.organization.import">
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Import Repository...</emphasis> - clones the
                            Repository and makes it available in the Git Repository View. This menu
                            action is only available if the Repository has not already been cloned.
                            All actions that affect the Repository (pull, commit, push, etc.) can
                            then be performed from the Git Repository View.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Create Project...</emphasis> - creates a new
                            Project with information collected from the following dialog:</para>
                        <figure>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="images/Eclipse/KieNavigator/Image15.png"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject>
                        </figure>
                        <para>If the “Import the Project” checkbox is checked, the Project will be
                            created in the local Repository and then created, and opened in the
                            local workspace. If unchecked, the Project is only created in the local
                            Repository; it can then be “imported” at a later time. Note that the
                            Project will become “visible” in the Kie web console immediately, but
                            the Project contents will only be available on the server after
                            Repository changes are committed and pushed upstream.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Remove Repository...</emphasis> - removes the
                            selected Repository from its containing Organizational Unit. The user
                            will be prompted to optionally delete the Repository from the
                            server.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Show in Git Repository View</emphasis> - opens
                            the Git Repositories View and highlights the selected Repository in that
                            view if it is available.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Properties</emphasis> - displays the Repository
                            Properties dialog (see the <link
                                linkend="shared.Eclipse.KieNavigator.properties.repository">Property
                                Pages</link> section below.)</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Project</title>
            <para>This context menu is only available if the Project has not yet been “Imported”
                that is, it has not yet been created in the local workspace.</para>
            <figure>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/Eclipse/KieNavigator/Image16.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Import Project</emphasis> - creates a local
                            workspace project that references the selected Project in the
                            Repository. This makes the project available for use. If a project with
                            the same name already exists in the workspace, the newly selected
                            Project can not be imported.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Delete Project...</emphasis> - deletes the
                            selected Project and removes it from its containing Repository.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Properties</emphasis> - displays the Project
                            Properties dialog (see the <link
                                linkend="shared.Eclipse.KieNavigator.properties.project">Property
                                Pages</link> section below.)</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </para>
            <para>Once a Project has been “Imported”, it becomes synchronized with the other Eclipse
                resource viewers as well (e.g. Project Explorer, Java Package Explorer, Eclipse
                Navigator, etc.) and any changes made in any of these viewers will also be reflected
                in the Kie Navigator View and vice-versa. The screenshot below illustrates this
                effect:</para>
            <figure>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/Eclipse/KieNavigator/Image17.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
        </section>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="shared.Eclipse.KieNavigator.properties">
        <title>Property Pages</title>
        <para>This section describes all of the property pages for each entry type in the Kie
            Navigator tree.</para>
        <section xml:id="shared.Eclipse.KieNavigator.properties.server">
            <title>Server</title>
            <figure>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/Eclipse/KieNavigator/Image18.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>

            <para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Server Name:</emphasis>the server name as
                            defined in the WST Servers Viewer. This can not be changed.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Host Name:</emphasis>the name of the machine on
                            which the app server is running. This is also managed from the WST
                            Servers Viewer.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Username/Password:</emphasis>login credentials
                            for the Kie web app. This is used to make REST calls to the Kie web
                            service.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Trust connections to this Server:</emphasis>if a
                            host is not known as a trusted site, the ssh protocol will prompt the
                            user to verify that this is a trusted site. Setting this checkbox
                            disables the prompt. The host can also be entered into the ssh
                            configuration as a trusted site to avoid this problem.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">KIE Application Name:</emphasis>the name of the
                            Kie web app; the Kie Navigator will try the following application names
                            by default to determine the app name:</para>
                        <itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>kie-wb</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>kie-drools-wb</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>kie-jbpm-wb</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>business-central</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>drools-console</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>jbpm-console</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>jboss-brms</para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>
                        <para>However, since the user has the option of renaming the Kie web app
                            during installation, Kie Navigator may not be able to discover the
                            actual name. This field is intended for the case where the web app name
                            has been user-defined.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Use default Git Repository Path:</emphasis>when
                            this checkbox is set, repositories will be cloned into the directory
                            configured by Git (see the Eclipse User Preferences for Git.) When
                            unchecked, the directory used in the following field will be used
                            instead.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Git Repository Path:</emphasis>the directory to
                            use for cloning repositories from this server; this field is only
                            enabled if the “Use default Git Repository Path” checkbox is unset. Note
                            that since it is possible to have many servers (e.g. production, test,
                            etc.) with a similar organizational structure, the chances of repository
                            name collisions are high. It is therefore suggested to use a different
                            repository directory for each server. By default, the server name is
                            appended to the default Git repository path, to give a unique directory
                            name for each server.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="shared.Eclipse.KieNavigator.properties.organization">
            <title>Organizational Unit</title>
            <figure>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/Eclipse/KieNavigator/Image19.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>These fields correspond to the Organizational Unit definition in the Kie web app.
                Note that only the Owner and Default Group ID can be changed.</para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="shared.Eclipse.KieNavigator.properties.repository">
            <title>Repository</title>
            <figure>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/Eclipse/KieNavigator/Image20.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>These fields correspond to the Repository definition in the Kie web app. The
                property page also shows the remote and local Git repository locations. Note that
                only the description and login credentials can be changed.</para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="shared.Eclipse.KieNavigator.properties.project">
            <title>Project</title>
            <figure>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/Eclipse/KieNavigator/Image21.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>These fields correspond to the Project definition in the Kie web app. Currently
                none of these fields can be updated on the web server due to REST API
                limitations.</para>
            <para>If a Project has been imported, this property page is shown in the context of the
                Eclipse project properties, as shown here:</para>
            <figure>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/Eclipse/KieNavigator/Image22.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
        </section>
    </section>
</section>
