<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section version="5.0" xml:id="ProcessManagement"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://www.docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink http://www.docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/xlink.xsd"
         xml:base="../" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:ns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  

         <title>Process Management</title>
         
         <para>This chapter describes the screens related with the creation and management of 
                process definitions and process instances. 
         </para>
         <para>
                Once you have modelled, configured all the technical details and build and deployed your projects containing your business processes you 
             should be able to see all the available process definitions in the Process Definition List. For all the process definitions listed in the 
             Process Definitions List you will be able to inspect the Process Definition details and start as many Process Instances as needed.
                The following sections describes the features provided by all the screens in charge of the manipulation of process definitions and
             process instances.
                You can find these screens under the <emphasis role="bold">Process Management</emphasis> Menu, in the jBPM Console NG or in KIE Workbench.
         </para>
         
         <para>
                You can find the source code related with the process definition and instances manupilation inside this module:
                <link xlink:href="http://github.com/droolsjbpm/jbpm-console-ng/tree/master/jbpm-console-ng-process-runtime">
                    http://github.com/droolsjbpm/jbpm-console-ng/tree/master/jbpm-console-ng-process-runtime
                </link>
                Feel free to report issues, send Pull Requests and get in contact with the team via comments in github.
         </para>
         
         
         <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                       <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role=""
                                  fileref="images/Console/process-management.png"/>
                </imageobject>
         </mediaobject>
         
         <section>
                <title>Process Definitions</title>
                
                <para>The process definition section is composed by two main screens: the Process Definition Lists and the
                       Process Definition Details.</para>
                
                <section>
                       <title>The Process Definition List</title>
                       <para> The process definition list shows all the available process definitions that were deployed into the platform. 
                              Look at the Deployments section for more information about how to check all the deploymed units available in the platform runtime. </para>
                       
                       <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                   <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role=""
                                          fileref="images/Console/process-definitions-list.png"
                                          maxwidth="700"/>
                            </imageobject>
                     </mediaobject>
                       
                       <para>You can click in the list rows to access to the details of the process definition. </para>
                       
                </section>
                
                <section>
                       <title>The Process Definition Details</title>
                       <para> The process definition details shows all the available information about the process definition. You can consider this
                              screen as a brief about the process model. You can quickly see if there is a Sub Process associated with it, or how many users and groups
                              are participating in the selected definition. 
                       </para>
                       
                       <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                   <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role=""
                                          fileref="images/Console/process-definitions-details.png"
                                          maxwidth="700"/>
                            </imageobject>
                     </mediaobject>
                       <para>Notice that you can View the Process Model (Read Only mode) using the Options Menu in the top bar. You can also
                              look at all the process instances for the selected process definition by going to Options -> View Process Instances.
                       </para>
                       
                       
                       <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                   <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role=""
                                          fileref="images/Console/process-model.png"
                                          maxwidth="700"/>
                            </imageobject>
                     </mediaobject>
                </section>
                
                <section>
                     <title>Creating Process Instances</title>
                       <para> You can create new Process Instances from the Process Definition List (Action Column), from the Process Definition Detail view or from
                           the Process Instance. </para>
                       
                       <mediaobject>
                              <imageobject>
                                     <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role="" 
                                            fileref="images/Console/process-definitions-new-instance.png"  maxwidth="700" />
                                     
                              </imageobject>
                       </mediaobject>
                       <para>When you create a Process Instance usually a Form will be presented to introduce the information required
                              by the process to be started. Once you complete the required information and click on the Submit button, the instance will be created and
                              the details of the Process Instance will be displayed on top of the Process Definition Details. 
                       
                       </para>
                </section>
         </section>
         <section>
             <title>Process Instances</title>
                
             <para>The process instances section is composed by two main screens: the Process Instance Lists and the
                 Process Instance Details. In this case the Process Instance Details provides several tabs with the 
                 runtime information related with the process. </para>
             <mediaobject>
                 <imageobject>
                     <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role="" 
                                                fileref="images/Console/process-instances-list.png"  maxwidth="700" />
                                     
                 </imageobject>
             </mediaobject>
             <section>
             <para>
                 Each row inside the process instance list represent a running process instance from a particular Process Definition. 
                 Each execution is differentiated from all the others by the internal state of the information that the process is manipulating. 
                 In order to inspect this information you can click in each row to see the process instance details.
             </para>   
             <mediaobject>
                 <imageobject>
                     <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role="" 
                                                fileref="images/Console/process-instances-details.png"  maxwidth="700" />
                                     
                 </imageobject>
             </mediaobject>   
             <para>
                 As you can see the Process Instance Detail first tab gives you a quick overview about what is going on inside the process. This is by showing 
                 the current state of the instance and also the current activity that is being executed.
                 The process variables tab display all the process variables  that are being manipulated by the instance with the exception of the variables that contains
                 documents. 
             </para> 
             <mediaobject>
                 <imageobject>
                     <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role="" 
                                                fileref="images/Console/process-instances-variables.png"  maxwidth="700" />
                                     
                 </imageobject>
             </mediaobject>
             <para>
                 If the process contains a variable of the type: org.jbpm.Document it will be listed in the Documents tab, for easy access, download and manipulation
                 of the attached documents. Notice that at this point you cannot attach new documents to currently running instances, but this feature will be added in future versions.
             </para> 
             <mediaobject>
                 <imageobject>
                     <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role="" 
                                                fileref="images/Console/process-instances-documents.png"  maxwidth="700" />
                                     
                 </imageobject>
             </mediaobject>  
             <para>
                 Finally, the Logs tab shows two types of logs for different end users. There are two types of Logs available inside the tab: Business and Technical.
                 
             </para>
               
             <mediaobject>
                 <imageobject>
                     <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role="" 
                                                fileref="images/Console/process-instances-logs.png"  maxwidth="700" />
                                     
                 </imageobject>
             </mediaobject>        
             <para>
                 To complement the process logs you can open the Process Model that shows the completed activies in grey and the current activities
                 highlighted in red.
             </para> 
             
            <mediaobject>
                 <imageobject>
                     <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role="" 
                                                fileref="images/Console/process-instances-running-model.png"  maxwidth="700" />
                                     
                 </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
             </section>
             <section>
                 <title>Process Instance List</title>
                 <para>This list works with the concept of view. A view is a set of visualization parameters that modify what items has to be displayed and
                     how the items details has to be shown.</para><para> A view embrace</para>
                 <itemizedlist>
                     <listitem>
                         <para>Columns to be shown</para>
                     </listitem>
                     <listitem>
                         <para>Items by page</para>
                     </listitem>
                     <listitem>
                         <para>Restrictions over the displayed process instances</para>
                     </listitem>
                     <listitem>
                         <para>A Name to be shown at tab name</para>
                     </listitem>
                     <listitem>
                         <para>A Description as title when the view is selected</para>
                     </listitem>
                 </itemizedlist>
                 <para>We find here different areas with different purposes:Filtering, general section configuration
                     and specific view parameter setting in the data grid presentation:</para>
                 <mediaobject>
                     <imageobject>
                         <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role=""
                                    fileref="images/Console/process-instances-areas.png"  maxwidth="700" />

                     </imageobject>
                 </mediaobject>
                 <section>
                     <title>Filtering. Views on tabs</title>
                     <para>Here, there are the available views as tabs. When a tab is selected, the related parameters are
                         applied to the data grid. Here we have include the Dataset technology for queries and its queries
                         editor as a powerful tool to create the filters</para>
                     <para>The user can remove existing tabs clicking the cross button near the tab name</para>
                     <mediaobject>
                         <imageobject>
                             <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role=""
                                        fileref="images/Console/process-instances-remove_tab.png"  maxwidth="700" />
                         </imageobject>
                     </mediaobject>
                     <para>A new view can be created clicking the last tab, over the '+' button. A New Items list popup appears
                         and lets the user introduce parameters related with the new tab like: the name, the description and the filter.</para>
                     <mediaobject>
                         <imageobject>
                             <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role=""
                                        fileref="images/Console/process-instances-create-tab-labels.png"  maxwidth="700" />
                         </imageobject>
                     </mediaobject>
                     <mediaobject>
                         <imageobject>
                             <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role=""
                                        fileref="images/Console/process-instances-create-tab-filter_1.png"  maxwidth="700" />
                         </imageobject>
                     </mediaobject>
                     <para>If the view has to include a restriction over a specific column, then the link 'Add new' has to be
                         selected. A drop down list with all the columns to create restrictions</para>
                     <mediaobject>
                         <imageobject>
                             <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role=""
                                        fileref="images/Console/process-instances-create-tab-filter_2.png"  maxwidth="700" />
                         </imageobject>
                     </mediaobject>
                     <para>Once the column is selected, depending of its type, a new dropdown list is open with the kind of restrictions
                         available for the selected column and the necessary form to add them.</para>
                     <mediaobject>
                         <imageobject>
                             <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role=""
                                        fileref="images/Console/process-instances-create-tab-filter_3.png"  maxwidth="700" />
                         </imageobject>
                     </mediaobject>
                     <para>One filter can include a list of different conditions over different columns and the editor allow remove each
                         one clicking th 'x' button near them</para>

                     <para>Once the view creation parameters are defined, the 'Ok' button makes the new view appears as a
                         new tab. </para>
                 </section>
                 <section>
                     <title>General section configuration. Auto refresh and default views restore</title>
                     <para>In this area, the user can create a new item (in this case process instance), can refresh manually
                         the view that is being displayed, can configure autorefresh option and can restore default filters.</para>
                     <mediaobject>
                         <imageobject>
                             <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role=""
                                        fileref="images/Console/process-instances-generalarea.png"  maxwidth="700" />

                         </imageobject>
                     </mediaobject>
                     <para>Auto refresh is a functionality that allows define how often the data grid has to be refresed.
                         The user can select one of the different values ( 1,5 or 10  minutes),or disable this feature, clicking 'Disable'.
                     If the auto refresh is enabled, then the last view displayed is refreshed after the amount of time defined.</para>

                     <para>The last button is the 'Restore default filters'. There is a set of predefined views that appears
                         the first time the user access to the section, in the case of process instances list they are: Active, Complete and Aborted.
                         The user can remove every view includind the default ones, but in this area the default views
                         can be restored clicking 'Restore default filters'.</para>
                 </section>
                 <section>
                     <title>Specific view configuration. Columns, Bulk actions, number of items</title>
                     <para>In this area the user can change dynamically the view editable parameters like visible columns,
                         or set the number  of items to show in a page.</para>
                     <mediaobject>
                         <imageobject>
                             <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role=""
                                        fileref="images/Console/process-instances-column_selector.png"  maxwidth="700" />

                         </imageobject>
                     </mediaobject>
                     <para> Here we have the posibility or execute bulk actions over
                         the items marked as selected. I this case the available actions are 'Abort' or 'Signal'</para>
                     <mediaobject>
                         <imageobject>
                             <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role=""
                                        fileref="images/Console/process-instances-specific-area.png"  maxwidth="700" />

                         </imageobject>
                     </mediaobject>
                     <para>The number of items to show in a page can be configurable too, from the page size dropdown list</para>
                     <mediaobject>
                         <imageobject>
                             <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role=""
                                        fileref="images/Console/process-instances-number-items.png"  maxwidth="700" />

                         </imageobject>
                     </mediaobject>
                 </section>

                 <section>
                     <title>Special filter in process instance list</title>

                     <para>There is an specific restriction than makes the process instance list view, have a different behaviour.
                         This happend when a filter over the column 'PROCESSID' is defined.</para>
                     <para>
                         In this case, the columns available to show have been incremented with the specified process variables which have value.
                         The user can then, view process instance variables from a specific process id, in the same grid
                         of the process instances.
                 </para>

                 <mediaobject>
                     <imageobject>
                         <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role=""
                                    fileref="images/Console/process-instances-process-id-variables.png"  maxwidth="700" />

                     </imageobject>
                 </mediaobject>
                 <para>

                 </para>
                 </section>
             </section>
         </section>
</section>
