<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section version="5.0" xml:id="jBPMExamplesHR"
       xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://www.docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink http://www.docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/xlink.xsd"
       xml:base="../" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
       xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
       xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
       xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:ns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
       <title>Human Resources Example</title>

       <para>
         The Human Resource Example's use case can be described as follows: A company wants to hire new developers. In this process, three departments (that is the Human resources, IT, and Accounting) are involved. These departments are represented by three users: Katy, Jack, and John respectively.
       </para>
       <figure>
         <title>Business Process</title>
         <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                       <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role=""
                              fileref="images/Examples/human-resources-high-level.png" width="700"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                  <para>Business process designed for the Human Resource Example's use case</para>
                </caption>
         </mediaobject>
       </figure>
       <para>
         Note that only four out of the six defined activities within the business process are User Tasks. User Tasks require human interaction. The other two tasks are Service Tasks, which are automated and connected to other systems.
       </para>
       <para>
         Each instance of the process will follow certain actions:
       </para>

       <itemizedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>
                  The human resources team performs the initial interview with the candidate
                </para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>
                  The IT department team performs the technical interview
                </para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>
                  Based on the output from the previous two steps, the accounting team creates a job proposal
                </para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>
                  When the proposal has been drafted, it is automatically sent to the candidate via email
                </para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>
                  If the candidate accepts the proposal, a new meeting to sign the contract is scheduled
                </para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>
                  Finally, if the candidate accepts the proposal, the system posts a message about the new hire using Twitter service connector
                </para>
              </listitem>
       </itemizedlist>
       <para>
         Note, that Jack, John, and Katy may represent any employee within the company with appropriate role assigned.
       </para>
       <section>
              <title>The KIE Project: human-resources</title>
              <figure>
                <title>Authoring Perspective</title>
                <mediaobject>
                  <imageobject>
                    <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role=""
                           fileref="images/Examples/human-resources-project-editor.png"
                           width="700"/>
                  </imageobject>
                  <caption>
                    <para>Project content in the Authoring Perspective</para>
                  </caption>
                </mediaobject>
              </figure>
              <para>The <guilabel>Authoring Perspective</guilabel> contains the <emphasis role="bold">hiring.bpmn2</emphasis>
                     process and a set of forms for each human task. You may explore these knowledge
                     assets by clicking on them. Notice that different editors open
                     for different types of assets. If you click on the Business Process file, the Process Designer opens:</para>
              <mediaobject>
                     <imageobject>
                            <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role=""
                                   fileref="images/Examples/human-resources-hiring-bpmn.png"
                                   width="700"/>
                     </imageobject>
              </mediaobject>
              <para>You may also explore the forms. Notice that the Form Modeller will be
                     opened, which allows you to edit the forms to fit your requirements.</para>
              <mediaobject>
                     <imageobject>
                            <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role=""
                                   fileref="images/Examples/human-resources-hr-interview-form.png"
                                   width="700" />
                     </imageobject>
              </mediaobject>
       </section>
       <section>
              <title>Building the Human Resources Example</title>
              <para>In order to build the Project, you need to go to the Authoring Perspective and open the Project Editor
                     panel: </para>
              <mediaobject>
                     <imageobject>
                            <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role=""
                                   fileref="images/Examples/human-resources-go-to-project-editor.png"
                                   width="400" />
                     </imageobject>
              </mediaobject>

              <para>Once you open the <guilabel>Project Editor</guilabel>, you will see in the top right corner of the
                     panel <guibutton>Build &amp; Deploy</guibutton>. This button allows you to
                     create a new JAR artifact that will be deployed to the runtime environment as a
                     new deployment unit. </para>
              <mediaobject>
                     <imageobject>
                            <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role=""
                                   fileref="images/Examples/human-resources-build-and-deploy.png"
                                   width="700" />
                     </imageobject>
              </mediaobject>
              <para>
                Once you get the visual notification that the project was built and deployed successfully, you may verify its presence in the <guilabel>Deployments</guilabel> tab.
                To do so, click <menuchoice><guimenu>Deploy</guimenu><guimenuitem></guimenuitem>Deployments</menuchoice>.
              </para>
              <mediaobject>
                     <imageobject>
                            <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role=""
                                   fileref="images/Examples/human-resources-go-to-deployments.png"
                                   width="200" />
                     </imageobject>
              </mediaobject>
              <para>You may find all the deployed units in the <guilabel>Deployments</guilabel> tab. When
                     you <emphasis>Build &amp; Deploy</emphasis> a project from the Project Editor, it is
                     automatically deployed using the default configurations. Therefore, Singleton
                     Strategy, the default KIE Base and the default KIE Session will be used. </para>
              <para>
                In case you wish a more advanced deployment, you may undeploy and re-deploy your artifacts using their GAV and selecting non-default settings.
                By doing so, you will be able to set a different strategy, or use non-default KIE Base or KIE Session.
              </para>

              <mediaobject>
                     <imageobject>
                            <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role=""
                                   fileref="images/Examples/human-resources-deployment-screen.png"
                                   width="700"/>
                     </imageobject>
              </mediaobject>

              <para> Once your artifact that contains the process definition is deployed, the
                     Process Definition will become available in <menuchoice><guimenu>Process Management</guimenu><guimenuitem>Process Definitions</guimenuitem></menuchoice>.
              </para>

       </section>
       <section>
              <title>Create a new Process Instance</title>
              <para>
                In order to create new Process Instances click <menuchoice><guimenu>Process Management</guimenu><guimenuitem>Process Definitions</guimenuitem></menuchoice>.
              </para>

              <para>The <guilabel>Process Definitions</guilabel> tab contains all the available process definitions in the runtime
                     environment. In order to add new process definitions, build and deploy a new project.
             </para>

             <figure>
               <title>Starting Process Instances</title>
               <mediaobject>
                      <imageobject>
                             <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role=""
                                    fileref="images/Examples/human-resources-process-definitions.png"
                                    width="700"/>
                      </imageobject>
                      <caption>
                        <para>
                          You may start process instances using any of the two highlighted options
                        </para>
                      </caption>
               </mediaobject>
             </figure>
              <para>
                Most processes require additional information to create a new process instance. This is done through forms.
                For this project, fill in the name of the candidate that is to be interviewed.
              </para>
              <mediaobject>
                     <imageobject>
                            <imagedata align="center" format="PNG" role=""
                                   fileref="images/Examples/human-resources-new-instance-form.png"
                                   width="400" />
                     </imageobject>
              </mediaobject>
              <para>
                By clicking the start button, a new process instance will be created. This creates the first task, that is available for the Human Resources team.
                In order to see the task, you need to logout and log in as a user with the appropriate role assigned, that is someone from the Human Resources.
              </para>
              <para>
                Once you have started the process, you may interact with the human tasks. To do so, click <menuchoice><guimenu>Task</guimenu><guimenuitem>Tasks</guimenuitem></menuchoice>.
                Note that in order to see the tasks in the task list, you need to belong to specific user groups, for which the task is designed.
                For example, the HR Interview task is visible only for the members of the HR group, and the Tech Interview Task is visible only to the members of the IT group.
              </para>
       </section>

</section>
